# Priyanka Saggu

### **About**

# Summary

Resourceful DevOps enthusiast, having experience working with highly distributed infrastructure on hybrid cloud platforms. Having an years long experience as a DevOps Engineer, I've been writing fully automated product releases, with minimal interference on the client enterprise end. As a summer trainee at Dgplug, I have set up and managed multiple Linux-based servers. Wrote Infrastructure as Code(IaC) to automate setting up of tightly-secured and SSH-hardened systems/servers. Also, have an experience with On-Prem deployment environments setup using Rancher. And I'm an Outreachy'19 alumna at GNOME Foundation too.

### **Personal Info**

- Email: priyankasaggu11929@gmail.com
- Website: https://priyankasaggu11929.github.io/
- Gitlab-gnome: https://gitlab.gnome.org/priyankasaggu119
- Gitlab-salsa: https://salsa.debian.org/priyankasaggu119-guest
- Github: https://github.com/Priyankasaggu11929/
- Resume.pdf: download here

# **Experience**

### **AtlanHQ**

- DevOps Engineer (May' 20 Present)
- DevOps Engineer Intern (Feb' 20 May' 20)

Working at a DataOps organisation, has resulted in a high level of expertise in writing & maintaining infrastructure for industrial use. In one instance, I've worked on optimizing the cost of running an entire data cataloging & discovery stack by 40%, bringing in a lite version of the product.

### **GNOME Foundation**

• Outreachy'19 Intern - (Dec' 19 - Mar' 20)

#### GeeksforGeeks, Noida

• Graphics designer intern - 2018

# **Community Learning & Contributions**

### **Dgplug Summer Training**

#### 2018-Present

- Set up and managed multiple Linux distribution servers.
- Wrote Ansible scripts to automatically update system components and setup production environments.
- Set up a WriteFreely multi-user instance behind reverse-proxy.
- Set up multiple Docker containers, orchestrated using Docker Swarm, for carrying out test deployments.
- Wrote Infrastructure as Code (IaC) to setup SSH-hardened servers.
- Contributed to lymworkbook a Vagrant lab environment in setting up a few basic level sys-admins problems.
- Setup OpenVpn service, creating both OpenVPN server and Certificate Authority (CA) server on different machines.

• Setup On-Prem multi-cluster orchestriation platform for microservices applications deployment using Rancher & managed kubernetes cluster.

### **Gnome** - gtranslator

#### 2019-Present

- Enhanced UI by revamping existing widgets in accordance with Gnome Human Interface Guidelines(HIG).
- Entirely redesigned the old search and replace bar dialog to a new sliding overlay style custom widget, using libdazzle library.

#### **Debian**

#### 2019

- Packaged 4 django/flask dependency python modules under Debian-Python-Modules-Team (DPMT).
- Packaged and updated 5+ ruby-gems for Debian-Diaspora project under Debian-Ruby-Team (DRT).
- Contributed to the Debian-gitlab project under Debian-javascript-team (DJT). Improved old node modules, packaged new ones and was constantly involved in testing of Debian-gitlab for then-stable version release.

# Skills/ Keywords

- Linux: Debian family (Ubuntu, Debian Buster), Red Hat family (CentOS)
- Scripting: Bash and utils, Python
- Backend: Python (Django)
- Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript (JQuery, PhaserJS)
- GUI Toolkit: GTK+ 3 in pure C
- Databases: MySQL, SQLite
- Web Application servers/proxies: Nginx, Apache2
- Version control systems: Git
- Markup & Documentation: LaTeX, Pandoc, Markdown
- **DevOps**: Kubernetes, Rancher, Ansible, Docker, Docker Swarm, Helm/Helm Charts, Prometheus & Grafana, Velero, Weave Cloud, Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE), RabbitMQ, Replicated/KOTS, CircleCI, Github Actions
- Misc: Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS), OpenCV, Java-J2SE

### Education

• B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering

Deenbandhu Chhotu Ram University of Science & Technology, Murthal (Sonepat), Haryana 2015-2019

AISSCE (12th-PCM)

Govt. Model Senior Secondary School, Sector 35-D, Chandigarh (U.T.) 2014-2015

• AISSE (10th)

S.B.P. D.A.V Centenary Public School, Fatehabad, Haryana 2012-2013

# **Conferences/ Events**

- 2019 PyCon, India
- 2019 DebUtsav, Delhi
- 2017 International Conference on Textile Advances-TAI India

### Additional activities

- Regional Head Haryana, GirlScript Foundation Private Limited (2019-2020).
- Organised Python 101 BootCamp in Haryana state-level technical fest, Technova.
- Attended IWD'19 event in Google, Gurugram. Also, the women's mega day meetup in Microsoft, Gurugram.

# Writings

### Self

- Automating private dataproc cluster deployment having Presto Installation (on GCP)!
- Custom GCP type provider for automating VPC Network Peering creation!
- Parse Server On-Premise Deployment
- A guide to a "safer" SSH!
- Consul Key-Value Store!
- Let's get started with iptables!
- Automating WordPress Installation Through Ansible!
- Setting up WriteFreely multi-user instance in production!

### **Publications**

- Introduction to Xamarin | A Software for Mobile App Development and App Creation
- Flutter | An Introduction to the Open Source SDK by Google

### References

• Chandan Kumar, OpenStack/RDO developer, Red Hat, chkumar AT redhat DOT com